<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="frame.xsl"?>
<frame cBy="MJE" cDate="03/17/2016 06:18:07 PDT Thu" name="Identity" ID="3000" xsi:schemaLocation="../schema/frame.xsd" xmlns="http://framenet.icsi.berkeley.edu" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <definition>&lt;def-root&gt;An &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt; of some type is conceived of as having an &lt;fen&gt;Identity&lt;/fen&gt;, defined as the unique feature that distinguishes each &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt; from all other instances of its type.  &lt;fen&gt;Identity&lt;/fen&gt; persists across time and remains constant for an &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt; despite arbitrary changes in other attributes of the &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt;.  Establishing &lt;fen&gt;Identity&lt;/fen&gt; answers the question "which".

&lt;ex&gt;I still have questions about &lt;fex name="Instance"&gt;her&lt;/fex&gt; &lt;t&gt;&lt;fex name="Identity"&gt;identity&lt;/fex&gt;&lt;/t&gt; .&lt;/ex&gt;
&lt;ex&gt;&lt;fex name="Identity"&gt;&lt;t&gt;Which&lt;/t&gt;&lt;/fex&gt; &lt;fex name="Instance"&gt;dinner&lt;/fex&gt; did you choose ?&lt;/ex&gt;

&lt;fen&gt;Identity&lt;/fen&gt; is not the same as appearance or name (if the &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt; even has such), although these attributes of the &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt; may be useful in establishing &lt;fen&gt;Identity&lt;/fen&gt;.  &lt;fen&gt;Identity&lt;/fen&gt; can be established knowing the totality of the history of an &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt;; however, this is impractical and usually proxies like name and appearance are used.  For the &lt;fen&gt;Identity&lt;/fen&gt; of humans, history sufficient to establish &lt;fen&gt;Identity&lt;/fen&gt; can usually be satisfactorily established by documents associated with the person, often with information like appearance and name, though use of such documents contributes to the problem of multiple identities, only one of which is considered legitimate or "true" in a given context.  Just as we would consider &lt;ment&gt;gun&lt;/ment&gt; in "fake gun" to contain a reference to the normal concept of Weapon, we consider &lt;ment&gt;identity&lt;/ment&gt; in "multiple identities" to belong to this frame, even if only one of the identities is legitimate.  Multiple identities can also exist when each is primarily associated with a fragment or aspect of the history and attributes of an entity, and the "true" identity might be very much debatable; in most such cases, there are different names associated with the different identities, as in the case of stage names or Ellis-Island names, but sometimes, the different "identities" go under the same name (e.g., some members of secret societies). While these may be considered different identities, they refer to the same person.
&lt;ex&gt;&lt;/ex&gt;
This frame is intended to cover cases where an entity is mentioned, but the category it fits is what is actually meant:

&lt;ex&gt;We need to determine the &lt;t&gt;&lt;fex name="Identity"&gt;identity&lt;/fex&gt;&lt;/t&gt; &lt;fex name="Instance"&gt;of the metal used in the picture frame&lt;/fex&gt; .&lt;/ex&gt;

In this case, it is not individual identity of the physical hunk of metal that is intended to be in question, but rather the category that the hunk of metal fits into; i.e., the specific element or elemental composition of the metal is what is in question.  Such sentences should be understood as determining which &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt; of the supercategory is intended.

&lt;ex&gt;&lt;/ex&gt;
This frame is not intended to cover related, and often more common, uses of the word "identity" such as "sexual identity", "national identity", or "brand identity", which do not refer to a unique identity of an &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt;, or even the identity of a supercategory of the &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt;, but rather refer to the specific properties of an &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt; that are considered very important for how the &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt; operates in aggregate.  Thus, uses like "losing your identity" are not intended to be covered by this frame.&lt;/def-root&gt;</definition>
    <FE bgColor="0000FF" fgColor="FFFFFF" coreType="Core" cBy="MJE" cDate="03/17/2016 06:18:07 PDT Thu" abbrev="ci" name="Instance" ID="16806">
        <definition>&lt;def-root&gt;The instance of a type or out of a set that is currently under discussion.&lt;/def-root&gt;</definition>
    </FE>
    <FE bgColor="008000" fgColor="FFFFFF" coreType="Core-Unexpressed" cBy="MJE" cDate="03/17/2016 06:47:04 PDT Thu" abbrev="" name="Identity" ID="16811">
        <definition>&lt;def-root&gt;The feature of each &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt; that distinguishes it from all others.  Notionally, each &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt; has a separate &lt;fen&gt;Identity&lt;/fen&gt;, although in practice many &lt;fen&gt;Instance&lt;/fen&gt;s cannot be distinguished from each other.&lt;/def-root&gt;</definition>
    </FE>
    <frameRelation type="Inherits from"/>
    <frameRelation type="Is Inherited by"/>
    <frameRelation type="Perspective on">
        <relatedFrame ID="3001">Identity_scenario</relatedFrame>
    </frameRelation>
    <frameRelation type="Is Perspectivized in"/>
    <frameRelation type="Uses"/>
    <frameRelation type="Is Used by"/>
    <frameRelation type="Subframe of"/>
    <frameRelation type="Has Subframe(s)"/>
    <frameRelation type="Precedes"/>
    <frameRelation type="Is Preceded by"/>
    <frameRelation type="Is Inchoative of"/>
    <frameRelation type="Is Causative of"/>
    <frameRelation type="See also"/>
    <lexUnit status="Created" POS="N" name="identity.n" ID="18673" lemmaID="18882" cBy="MJE" cDate="03/17/2016 07:58:21 PDT Thu">
        <definition>FN: the feature (of each enitity) that is distinct from all other instances of the type.</definition>
        <sentenceCount annotated="0" total="0"/>
        <lexeme order="1" headword="false" breakBefore="false" POS="N" name="identity"/>
    </lexUnit>
</frame>